我长久以来的恐惧…
I have long feared...
就是我旧日的罪愆会回来纠缠我
...that my sins would return to visit me.
代价之高，我无法承受
And the cost is more than I can bear.
决战　　  时刻
山缪！信差来了！
Samuel! A postrider!
“R” An "R."
很好
Good.
这个呢？
What about this one?
谢谢　　不客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
爸爸…
Father! Father!
9磅，11盎司，好极了
Nine pounds, eleven ounces. That's perfect. Perfect.
爸爸，有信差！
Father, a postrider!
你南田的种子种好了吗？
Did you finish planting the field?
种好一半多了
More than half.
偷偷去游泳，浪费了一些时间吧？
Those swimming breaks really cut into the day, don't they?
告诉你了吧
Told you.
托马斯
Thomas.
等爸爸
Wait for Father.
对不起
Sorry.
1776年，南卡罗莱纳州
伊丽莎白・普顿・马汀之墓 卒于1773年2月18日，享年35岁
那就是了，北极星
That's her. The North Star.
看到了吗？
See?
你要从北斗七星的最前面两颗星开始看
You start from the front two stars of the Big Dipper.
然后往上数
And then you count up.
数到五指的宽度时…
You count up five finger lengths...
就在那儿了
...and it's right there.
它会一直俯视着我们
And she'll always be looking down on us.
永远保护我们
And protect us. Forever.
来，睡觉了
Come. Into bed.
晚安，晚安，梅格
Good night. Good night, Meg.
让她知道妈在那儿会好得多
It helps her to know Mother's there.
晚安
Good night.
邮件里有什么？
So what was in the mail?
纽约州和宾夕法尼亚的议会…
"The New York and Pennsylvania assemblies...
在辩论独立事宜
...are debating independence."
中部的殖民地呢？
What about the middle colonies?
在切斯特城，他们烧毁了海关
"In Chestertown, they burned the customs house...
严惩了两名官员
...and tar and feathered two magistrates.
他们被烧死
They died of... They died of burns."
真是蠢货
Damn fools.
你是说谁？作者还是那两个官员？
Who? The writers or the magistrates?
有没谈及大陆会议的事？
What does it say about the Continental Congress?
上面说会在七月宣布独立
It says here they'll make a declaration of independence by July.
彼德・库本加入独立军了
Peter Cuppin joined the Continentals.
他才十七，比我还小一岁
He's 17, a year younger than I.
国民大会开会，我被叫到查理士城去了
Well, the assembly's been convened, so I've been called to Charles Town.
我们要去查理士城？　对
- We're going to Charles Town? - We are.
我们明早就动身
We leave in the morning.
夏绿蒂
Charlotte.
孩子在这里
The children are here.
谢谢你
Thank you.
夏绿蒂阿姨！
Aunt Charlotte!
玛格莉特，威廉，看看你们
Margaret, William, look at you.
好想你
Missed you.
他们长得好大，你给他们吃了什么啊？
They're huge. What have you been feeding them?
他们的种好，因为是遗传自母亲
Well, they're from good stock. On their mother's side, of course.
谢谢，进来吧，我有不少好东西
Thank you. Come inside. Wait until you see what I have.
给我们的礼物？　慢慢来
- Presents? Presents for us? - Move slowly.
你们看好那些野蛮人，好吗？
Keep an eye on these heathens, will you?
对不起
Sorry.
我帮你准备了这个，苏珊，是你妈的
I have this for you, Susan. It belonged to your mother.
她还是不开口？
She's still not talking?
没错
No.
看到你，我的感觉真好
It does me good to see you.
看，那是佳百列
Look, there's Gabriel.
佳百列
Gabriel.
吊死乔治国王！
Hang King George!
哈利・布尔在招兵
Harry Burwell is here recruiting.
州长已经发誓，如果议会给大陆军
The governor has vowed if the assembly votes a single shilling...
支持一分钱，就会解散议会
...to the Continental Army, he'll dissolve the body.
那是否使我们在宾州的代表…
Wouldn't that force our delegates in Philadelphia
一定要投独立的票？
to vote for independence?
是的
Yes.
使我们在麻省附近发生战争
Send us off to war alongside Massachusetts.
处死乔治国王！
Get King George!
把他们全都吊死！　一个都不要放过！
- Hang them all! - Hang the lot of them!
够了，很好，孩子，进去吧
That's enough. Very well, children, inside.
走吧，进去
Come along now. Inside now.
布尔指靠你的选票
Burwell will be counting on your vote.
他希望成为第一个当选的人
And he'll expect you to be the first to enlist.
是的，我想是
Yes, I imagine so.
对不起，这些野蛮人是…
I'm sorry, the heathens are...
他们非常渴望一个女人
They have long needed a woman in their lives.
一个妈妈
A mother.
特别是苏珊
Especially Susan.
我是彼得・霍尔
My name is Peter Howard.
我丧失了大部份的听力和我的左腿…
I lost most of my hearing and my left leg...
全都是为了法国和印第安人之间的战事
...fighting for the Crown in the French and Indian War.
乔治国王是怎么报答我的？
And how did King George reward me?
他用税废了我另一条腿
He cuts off my other leg with his taxes.
是你吗，霍华小姐？
Miss Howard, isn't it?
你知道我是谁，佳百列・马汀
You know who I am, Gabriel Martin.
我们最后一次见面，我才11岁
The last time you saw me, I was 11
你在我茶中加了墨水
and you put ink in my tea.
那应该是我弟弟吧，也许是山缪或纳森
I believe that was one of my younger brothers. Perhaps Samuel or Nathan.
是你，那让我的牙齿黑了一个月
It was you, and it turned my teeth black for a month.
我们就给乔治国王一个永生难忘的教训吧
- And send a message to King George he will never forget!
我们的第一个议题
Our first order of business...
也是最后的，让我们来投票表决征兵！
And our last, if we vote a levy!
安静…！
Order, order!
西门斯先生，你没有发言权
Mr. Simms, you do not have the floor.
首先是哈利・布尔上校对独立军的演说
First, an address by Colonel Harry Burwell of the Continental Army.
布尔上校
Colonel Burwell.
大家都知道我为什么来这儿
You all know why I'm here.
我不是个演说家
I'm not an orator.
我也不想说服大家接受我们作战的理由
And I would not try to convince you of the worthiness of our cause.
我是个军人
I'm a soldier.
我们正在作战
And we are at war.
我们在等宾州发表独立宣言
From Philadelphia, we expect a declaration of independence.
13个州中有8个州都决定出资…
8 of the 13 colonies have levied money...
赞助独立军
...in support of a continental army.
我希望南卡能够成为第9个州
I ask that South Carolina be the ninth.
麻州和维吉尼亚州也许在打仗…
Massachusetts and Virginia may be at war...
但是南卡不是！
...but South Carolina is not!
赞成…
Hear, hear.
这一场战争不是为争取一两个州的独立…
This is not a war for the independence of one or two colonies...
而是争取整个国家的独立
...but for the independence of one nation.
哪个国家呢？
And what nation is that?
美国！
An American nation!
没有这个国家，这么说是叛国
There is no such nation and to speak of one is treason.
我们是美国的国民
We are citizens of an American nation.
我们的权利却受到三千英哩外…
And our rights are being threatened...
暴君的威胁
...by a tyrant 3000 miles away.
霍华先生，请告诉我
Would you tell me, please, Mr. Howard...
我为什么要用三千哩外的暴君…
...why should I trade one tyrant 3000 miles away...
来换一英哩外的三千个暴君？
...for 3000 tyrants one mile away?
民选国会也能像国王一样
An elected legislature can trample
践踏我们的人权
a man's rights as easily as a king can.
马汀上尉…
Captain Martin...
我知道你很爱国
...I understood you to be a patriot.
如果你想知道我是否因遭重税而愤愤不平？
If you mean by "patriot," am I angry about taxation without representation?
是的，我很生气
Well, yes, I am.
美国是否该独立自主？
Should the American colonies govern themselves independently?
我认为他们可以也应该
I believe they can. And they should.
但若你问我是否该跟英国宣战…
But if you're asking me am I willing to go to war with England...
我的答复是否定的
...then the answer is most definitely no.
难道这就是在英法战争时…
This from the same Captain Benjamin Martin whose fury was so famous...
怒气勃发的马汀上尉说的话吗？
...during the Wilderness campaign?
当年我年少轻狂
I was intemperate in my youth.
节制很可能是恐惧的伪装
Temperance can be a disguise for fear.
米德顿先生，我和马汀上尉…
Mr. Middleton, I fought with Captain Martin...
一起在华盛顿将军的麾下打过仗
...under Washington in the French and Indian War.
这屋里没有任何人…
There's not a man in this room...
比他还值得我信任的
...or anywhere for that matter, to whom I would more willingly trust my life.
除了战争还有别的选择
There are alternatives to war.
我们可以向国王陈情
We take our case before the king.
我们可以跟他讲理　　我们试过了
- We plead with him. - We tried.
那我们应一试再试，极力避免战争
Well, then, we try again and again if necessary to avoid a war.
我参加过邦克山之役
I was at Bunker Hill.
英军推进了三次
The British advanced three times.
我们近距离杀了七百名英军
We killed 700 at point-blank range
但他们仍然攻下邦克山
and still they took the ground.
这是他们解决的方式
That is the measure of their resolve.
如果你的原则是坚持独立…
If your principles dictate independence...
那唯有作战一途
...then war is the only way.
战争是无法避免的
It is come to that.
对…
Hear, hear.
我有七个小孩
I have seven children.
内人已死
My wife is dead.
我去作战谁来照顾他们？
Now, who's to care for them if I go to war?
不光是没有小孩的男人才去作战
Wars are not fought only by childless men.
同意
Granted.
但请记下我的话
But mark my words.
这场战争将不是在前线进行…
This war will be fought, not on the frontier...
也不是在遥远的战场…
...or on some distant battlefield...
战火会在身边燃烧
...but amongst us.
在我们的家中燃烧
Among our homes.
我们的孩子们将会亲身体验战争的可怕
Our children will learn of it with their own eyes.
他们的童真将会和我们一起死去
And the innocent will die with the rest of us.
我不参战
I will not fight.
正因为如此，我不打算参与投票…
And because I will not fight, I will not cast a vote...
将别人送上战场
...that will send others to fight in my stead.
你的原则呢？
And your principles?
我是有孩子的人，我没有讲原则的权利
I'm a parent. I haven't got the luxury of principles.
我们一定要投票赞成征兵！
We must vote to levy!
28比l2！征兵通过了！
28 to 12! The levy passed!
你打算擅自入伍？
You intend to enlist without my permission?
是的
Yes, I do.
父亲，我还以为你是个有原则的人
Father, I thought you were a man of principle.
你有家室后自会明白
When you have a family of your own, perhaps you'll understand.
我有家室，也不会用他们来当挡箭牌
When I have a family of my own, I won't hide behind them.
他像他父亲小时候一样鲁莽
He's as imprudent as his father was at his age.
恐怕是这样
Regrettably so.
我会尽量将他收在我的羽翼之下
I'll see to it that he serves under me.
我叫他去做文官，或补给官之类的
Make him a clerk or quartermaster, something of that sort.
祝你好运
Good luck.
亲爱的托马斯，虽然过了许多年…
Dear Thomas: Though many seasons have passed...
但在查理士城见面，仿佛是昨日的事
...it seems like only yesterday when we last saw each other in Charles Town.
很遗憾听说，英军在康瓦理斯将军指挥下…
With sadness, I learned of its recent fall to the British...
打败我们的消息
...under General Cornwallis.
我今天接到夏绿蒂阿姨的信…
I received a letter from Aunt Charlotte...
告诉我…她在查理士城沦陷后锁上家门…
...saying she closed her home in Charles Town after the city fell...
然后搬到山提河畔的农场
...and moved to her plantation on the Santee.
在北边我们弹尽粮绝
Here in the north, our campaign has been marked by defeat and privation.
我们伤亡惨重
Our losses have been grievous.
我的好友彼德・库本，在伊丽莎白镇战死
My good friend, Peter Cuppin, fell at Elizabethtown.
他的死讯让我伤痛欲绝
His death has been difficult to bear.
我们即将和盖兹将军南进…
We will march south with General Gates...
和康瓦理斯将军的红衫军对决
...to fight the Redcoats under Cornwallis.
谢谢你，长官
Thank you, sir.
我羡慕你…
I envy you...
我羡慕你和战争毫无瓜葛
...your youth and distance from this cruel conflict of
而我却是这场战争的一部份
which I am a part.
但我觉得，自己有幸能够为自由而战
"But I am fortunate to be serving the cause of Liberty.
虽然我畏惧死亡…
And though I fear death...
但每天我都祈祷，我在必要时…
...each day in prayer I reaffirm my willingness...
能为自由捐躯
...to give my life in its service.
为我祷告
Pray for me.
为争取自由而祷告
But above all, pray for the cause.
爱你的哥哥，佳百列上
Your loving brother, Gabriel."
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
转身
Turn around.
现在还不行，托马斯
Not yet, Thomas.
那什么时候？
When?
等你17岁
Seventeen.
那还要两年，我已经等了两年
That's two years. It's already been two.
到时战争说不定结束了　　老天保佑
- The war could be over by then. - God willing.
17岁就17岁
All right. Seventeen.
好
All right.
请放回去
Put it back, please.
父亲？
Father?
威尔德尼斯堡发生了什么事？
What happened at Fort Wilderness?
收好
Put it away.
扔远一点　　你扔远一点，你来
- Throw it faster. - You throw it faster. You're the one...
玛格莉特，你让弟弟马上回来这里
Margaret, you go get your brothers back up here right now.
回屋去，快
Back to the house. Come on. Back to the house now.
跟我来，玛格莉特，快
Come with me. Margaret, go now.
他们快来了
They're going to come.
静点，坐下
Quiet. Sit down.
六磅炮
Six-pounders.
好多
Lots of them.
有多远？
How far away?
还远着呢，看来是瞄准别的方向
They're a long way off. They're most likely heading the other direction.
把枪收进去
Put those in the house.
他们可能朝这里来　　要我再说一遍吗？
- They might come this way. - Must I tell you again?
我们全躲在家里，懂吗？
Let's all stay close in to the house, all right?
我们要赶走英军
We'll have to fight them off.
父亲不会这么做吗？
Won't Father do that?
他们也许会杀了我们男人…
They'll probably kill us men...
凌虐你们女生
...and do Lord-knows-what to you women.
纳森！
Nathan!
慢慢转过来
Slowly turn.
父亲
Father.
艾比佳！
Abigale!
快去拿水和绷带
Water and bandages, fast.
你有在作战现场吗？
The battle. Were you there?
你有看见红衫军吗？
Have you seen any Redcoats?
还没有
No, not yet.
艾比佳，快去照顾孩子们
Abigale, the children, please.
孩子们，跟我上楼
Children, come. Upstairs.
盖兹带着我们直捣红衫军黄龙
Gates marched us straight at the Redcoats.
我们的防线失散了，被英军打得溃不成军
Our lines broke. The British Green Dragoons cut us to bits.
上级给我这些急件
I was given these dispatches.
我离开时，看到维吉尼亚正规军投降
As I left, I saw the Virginia Regulars surrender.
英军长驱直入
The Dragoons rode into them.
把他们杀光了
Killed them all.
两百多个人
Over 200 men.
我一定要把这些急件送到西尔斯堡
I have to get these dispatches to Hillsborough.
你不能骑马
You can't ride.
我不能留在这，我在这里会危及…
I can't stay here! It's not safe for...
开火！
Fire!
谢谢你们照顾国王的士兵
Thank you for the care of His Majesty's soldiers.
中尉，派一队人马送伤兵去看医生
Have a detachment take our wounded to our surgeons at Winnsboro.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
放火烧了那栋房子和谷仓
Fire the house and barns.
你们要是敢窝藏敌军，就会无家可归
Let it be known if you harbour the enemy you will lose your home.
乔治国王有令…
By order of King George...
任何只要为英国效力的美国奴隶
...all slaves of the American colonies who fight for the Crown...
只要我们战胜就能成为自由之身
...will be granted their freedom with our victory.
我们不是奴隶，是在这工作的自由人
We're not slaves. We work this land. We're freedmen.
那各位就是有幸为…
Then you're freedmen who will have the privilege...
英国军队效力的自由人了
...of fighting in the king's army.
敌军的快递，长官
Rebel dispatches, sir.
这是谁的？
Who carried this?
谁的？！
Who carried this?!
我的
I did, sir.
我受伤了，这些人照顾我
I was wounded. These people gave me care.
他们和这些密令没有关系
They have nothing to do with the dispatches.
带他去坎登，他是间谍
Take this one to Camden. He is a spy.
吊死他，尸首示众
Hang him, put his body on display.
他是个传令兵
He's a dispatch rider.
杀了活口把马留给英军
Destroy the livestock. Save the horses for the Dragoons.
上校，他是带着密令的制服传令兵
Colonel, this is a uniformed dispatch rider carrying a marked case.
他不能被视为间谍
He cannot be held as a spy.
我们不打算关他，我们要吊死他
Well, we won't hold him. We're going to hang him.
上校…　父亲！
- Colonel... - Father!
我懂了，他是你儿子
Oh, I see. He's your son.
也许你该教他什么叫做爱国
Perhaps you should've taught him something of loyalty.
上校，我求你根据作战时的规定…
Colonel, I beg you, please reconsider. By the rules of war...
你想知道什么叫作战规则吗？
Would you like a lesson, sir, in the rules of war?
也许你的小孩想上一课
Or perhaps your children would.
无此必要
No lesson is necessary.
长官
Sir.
那些受伤的叛军怎么办？
What of the rebel wounded?
杀了他们
Kill them.
父亲
Father.
父亲，快想想办法！
Father, do something!
安静！
Be quiet!
佳百列，快跑！
Gabriel, run!
等等！
Wait!
不！！
No!!
愚蠢的孩子
Stupid boy.
上尉
Captain.
托马斯！
Thomas!
来吧，孩子
Come, child.
不　　我不会留下这些孩子！
I'm not leaving these children!
手下留情！
Mercy!
准备！
Get ready!
举枪！
Present!
开火！
Fire!
你们都留在这里
All of you, stay here.
纳森，山缪
Nathan, Samuel.
玛格莉特
Margaret.
我要你们带着威廉和苏珊躲在田里
Hide in the fields with William and Susan.
若我黄昏时没回来，就去找夏绿蒂阿姨
If we're not back by sunset, take them to Aunt Charlotte's.
懂了吗？
- Is that clear? - Yeah.
孩子们
Boys.
这个地点不错
It's a good spot.
孩子们，听我说
Boys, listen to me.
我先开枪
I'll fire first.
我要你们先开枪打军官，再打士兵
Start with the officers and work your way down.
你们知道哪些是军官吧？
Can you tell the difference?
知道，父亲
Yes, Father.
知道　　很好
- Yes, Father. - Good.
山缪，在你开第一枪后就帮纳森装子弹
Samuel, after your first shot, reload for Nathan.
现在…
Now...
万一我有个三长两短，我要你们放下武器
...if anything should happen to me, drop your weapons.
能跑多快就跑多快
Run as quickly as you can.
回家去找弟弟，妹妹…
Get your brother and your sisters...
带他们去夏绿蒂阿姨家，懂吗？
...and take them to Aunt Charlotte's. Understood?
还记得我教你们怎么开枪吗？
What did I say about shooting?
瞄小目标失误就少
Aim small, miss small.
孩子们…
Boys...
山缪…
...Samuel...
不要慌
...steady.
上帝，保佑我又快又准
Lord, make me fast and accurate.
瞄小目标失误就少
Aim small, miss small.
上面，在右边！　在左边！
- On the right! - To the left!
在后面！
Behind us! Up on the ridge!
从右边来的！
Form right!
右转！
To the right!
向后转！
About face!
在右边的山上！
On the right to the rear!
向右转！
To the right!
开火！
Fire!
装子弹！　装子弹！
- Reload! - Reload!
在后面！
Behind you!
注意后面！
Look on the rear!
上帝
Lord...
我们祈祷您接受这个孩子
...we pray that you accept this child...
让他和他妈留在您身边
...and keep him at your side with his mother.
我们请求你收留他
We ask that you embrace him...
帮助我们理解你的仁慈
...and help us to understand the manner in which your mercy works.
原谅我们的罪行
And forgive us our sins.
我们以您的名义祈祷
This we ask in your name.
阿门
Amen.
我们印地安斥候带回来的二等兵
Sir, we have the private the Cherokee scouts brought in.
二等兵？
Private?
二等兵
Private.
我是青龙部队的威廉・塔维顿上校
Colonel William Tavington, Green Dragoons.
怎么了？谁干的好事？
What happened? Who did this?
他
Him.
当时情况一团乱
It was mad.
我也说不上来是谁干的
I couldn't tell you who it was.
冷静点…
Calm down. Calm down, man.
我们损失了20名皇家士兵
Twenty of His Majesty's soldiers are dead.
我要知道是怎么回事
And I need to know how.
他说有…　你在场吗？
- He said there was... - Were you there?
那就让他说
Then let him speak.
慢慢来，告诉我有多少人？
Take your time and tell me. How many were there?
是民兵吗？还是正规军？
Were they militia? Were they Regulars?
我不记得有多少人
I don't really remember how many.
也许只有一个
Maybe one.
一个人，真的吗？
One man. Really?
他在侧面攻击
He was in the flank.
似乎在我们周边游走
All around us.
又仿佛在我们之间
Amongst us.
他来无影去无踪，我几乎看不到他
I could barely see him. He was there, then he was gone.
他就这样消失了
He just vanished.
听起来像鬼不像人
Sounds more like a ghost than a man.
鬼
A ghost.
他是很像鬼
He was like a ghost.
够了
Enough.
波顿？带一队侦察队
Bordon? Take a patrol.
看看能不能在消息传开前抓到这个鬼
Capture this ghost before word of his exploits spread.
这是谁？　他是威尔金上尉
- Who's this? - Sir, this is Captain Wilkins.
他曾是英国民兵，说不定派得上用场
He was with the Loyalist Colonial Militia. He might be of use.
又一个殖民地居民
Another colonial.
威尔金上尉，你忠于哪一方？
Captain Wilkins, where do your loyalties lie?
我忠于英王和祖国
To king and country.
我为什么要信任一个出卖邻居的人？
Why should I trust a man who'd betray his neighbours?
我那些出卖英国的邻居…
Those neighbours of mine who stand against England...
罪该万死
...deserve to die a traitor's death.
咱们走着瞧吧
We'll see.
马汀先生！
Mr. Martin!
夏绿蒂小姐…！
Miss Charlotte!
你们安全了，睡吧
You're safe now. Try to sleep.
晚安
Good night.
父亲？
Father?
什么事？
Yes.
我杀了那些人
I killed those men.
你只是照我的话去做
You did what I told you to do.
那是你该做的，这没什么不对
You did what you had to. There was no wrong in it.
我很高兴杀了他们
I'm glad I killed them.
我真的很高兴
I'm glad.
睡吧
Get some rest.
山缪
Samuel.
你做了…没什么好觉得羞耻的事
You've done nothing for which you should be ashamed.
我什么都没做
I've done nothing.
所以我很羞愧
And for that, I am ashamed.
我们要去圣海伦纳
We'll go to Saint Helena.
在查理士城南边，是个自由奴隶岛
That's a free slave island just north of Charles Town.
就在英国人的眼皮底下
Right under the British noses.
他们不会想…　我要去加入他们
- They won't think of look... - I'm joining up with them.
佳百列
Gabriel.
不，你得留在这里
No. Your place is here now.
我要回去，我是个军人，这是我的职责
I'm going back. I'm a soldier, it's my duty.
你要对你的家庭负责
Your duty is to your family.
不准你弃我于不顾！
Don't you walk away from me, boy!
战争结束后我会来找你们
I'll find you when it's over.
我不准你去！
No, I forbid you to go!
我不是个小孩！　你是我的小孩！
- I'm not a child! - You're my child!
再见，父亲
Goodbye, Father.
佳百列
Gabriel.
托马斯死了
Thomas is dead.
到底要死多少人，你才肯听我的话？
How many more have to die before you'll heed my word?
我在失去我的家人
I'm losing my family.
父亲，你什么时候会回来？
When will you be back, Father?
我不知道
I don't know.
明天吗？
Tomorrow?
不是明天
No, not tomorrow.
乖乖祷告
You say your prayers.
我会的
I will.
照顾弟弟、妹妹和夏绿蒂阿姨
Take care of your brothers and sisters and your Aunt Charlotte.
我只能靠你了
I'm depending on you.
还有你，山缪
As I am on you, Samuel.
好
All right.
苏珊
Susan...
再见
...goodbye.
谢谢！
Thank you.
停！
Halt!
准备！
Make ready!
瞄准！
Take aim!
开火！
Fire!
我不会回去的
I'm not going back.
我也没有指望你回去
No, I didn't expect you would.
那个盖兹是个傻瓜
That Gates is a damn fool.
他在英国部队混了太久
He spent too many years in the British army.
居然想在旷野中击败红衫军，真疯狂
Going muzzle-to-muzzle with Redcoats in open field. It's madness.
停！
Halt!
准备！
Make ready!
举枪！
Present!
开火！
Fire!
这场战争在开始前就结束了
This battle was over before it began.
撤退！
Retreat!
这些乡巴佬真笨
These rustics are so inept.
差点害我们赢得毫无光彩
Nearly takes the honour out of victory.
差一点
Nearly.
大家好
Hello general, gentlemen.
今天是陛下和英格兰的荣耀之日
A glorious day for His Majesty and England.
塔维顿上校
Colonel Tavington.
总是太早
Always too early.
总是太渴求荣耀
Always too eager for glory.
渴求胜利
For victory, my lord.
我相信我们已经占领了地方
I believe we took the field.
下次，你要等我的命令
Next time, you'll wait for my command.
塔维顿上校好像更喜欢听自己下的命令
It appears that Colonel Tavington prefers to follow his own commands.
奥哈拉将军告诉我…
General O'Hara tells me...
你得了一个“屠夫”的称号
...you've earned the nickname "The Butcher" among the populous.
我们明天讨论
We'll discuss it tomorrow.
诸位，我的赞扬
Gentlemen, my compliments.
庆祝胜利　　说得好！
- To a victory. - Hear, hear.
压住他
Hold him firm.
你们的指挥官呢？　在那个帐篷里
- Where's your commanding officer? - That tent there.
那是个失败的行动
It's a lost cause.
班杰明・马汀
Benjamin Martin.
我不想听训
I'm in no mood for a lecture.
你们的盖兹将军呢？
Where's your General Gates now?
有人看到他骑着马朝东南方走了
The last anyone saw, riding hard northeast...
他的属下在百码后…苦苦追赶
...his staff 100 yards behind, trying to catch up.
现在由谁指挥？
So who's in command?
我
I am.
我想
I think.
你要下什么命令给我？
What are my orders?
班杰明，我们差一口气就输了
We're a breath away from losing this war, Benjamin.
华盛顿在莫瑞斯镇重整军备
In the north, Washington is reeling from Morristown.
他在躲一万两千名红衫军
He's running and hiding from 12,000 Redcoats.
我们在南方的军队又被康瓦理斯打散了
In the south, Cornwallis has broken our back.
他攻陷查理士城时，俘掳了我们五千弟兄
Captured over 5000 of our troops when he took Charles Town.
他也击溃了唯一挡在他和纽约间的军队
And he destroyed the only army between him and New York.
我们无力阻挡他长驱直入击败华盛顿军队
Nothing will stop him from heading north to finish off Washington.
除非想办法把康瓦理斯留在南方
Unless we can keep Cornwallis in the south
直到法军抵达
till the French arrive.
他们答应要派一支舰队和一万名士兵来
They've promised a fleet and 10,000 troops.
何时？
When?
最快还要六个月
Six months at the earliest.
你相信法国人会言而有信？
You trust the French to keep their word?
那当然
Absolument.
班杰明・马汀，这位是维伦少校
Benjamin Martin. Major Jean Villeneuve.
他是法国第七步兵连的，来帮我们训练民兵
French Seventh Light Foot. He will help train the militia.
你是维尔德尼斯的英雄，久仰了
The hero of Fort Wilderness. Your reputation precedes you.
你真的想用民兵来阻止康瓦理斯推进？
You really expect to hold Cornwallis here using just militia?
不是我，是你
Not me. You.
哈利，他们不是军人，是农民
They're not soldiers, they're farmers.
让英军通过…对他们比较好
They'd be better off letting the British march through.
没错，但形势不允许
They'd be better off, but the cause wouldn't.
康瓦理斯手下有多少人？
How many men does Cornwallis have?
八千名步兵
8000 infantry.
六百名骑兵
Around 600 cavalry.
我任命你为上校
I'm giving you a field commission as a colonel.
长官，可以把我儿子派到我的部队吗？
Might I request that you transfer my son under my command?
长官，不，我…
Sir, no, I...
就这么定了
That's done.
谢谢
Thank you.
上校，我已经当了两年兵
Colonel, I've been a soldier for two years.
我当过斥候骑兵，狙击兵，清道兵
As a scout, horseman, marksman, scavenger.
是吗？　我在正规军比较有发展
- Is that so? - I'd be of better use with Regulars.
你是从哪儿学会骑马，开枪的？
Where'd you learn all that riding, shooting, scavenging?
是我父亲教的
My father taught me.
他有没有教你如何谦虚？
Teach you any humility?
他试过，但我不受教
He tried. It didn't take.
他也教你认从这到查理士城的每条小路…
He also taught you every trail between here and Charles Town...
所以才会把你调过来
...which is why he transferred you.
我们放话出去，我们从山提河南岸开始…
We'll put the word out. Start on the south side of...
分头进行比较快
We'll cover more ground if we split up.
很好，下士
Very well, corporal.
你去哈利斯维尔、潘布克、维克菲尔德
You take Harrisville, Pembroke, Wakefield.
我从北边开始，到黑沼泽会合
I'll start on the north side. Meet at the mission in Black Swamp.
下士
Corporal.
小心点
Be careful.
遵命
Yes, sir.
你有孩子吗？
You have children?
法国人
French.
这从山上…
It skirts the mountain and then...
一直到这里的水边…
...extends down towards the headwater here...
跨越俄亥俄河
...and right across to the far bank of the Ohio River.
一共十万英亩
It's 100,000 acres.
好大一片土地啊
It's an imposing land grant, my lord.
你可以自己成立一个小国家
You will be a country unto yourself.
国王真的很大方
His Majesty is most generous.
但是您在战争中的表现也当之无愧
Though your service in this war more than warrants such a gift.
是的，国王对为他效命的人…
Yes, this is how His Majesty rewards those...
就是这么大方
...who fight for him as gentlemen.
我想我也有一天能得到奖赏吧
I dare to presume my own meagre contributions will be rewarded one day.
你想得太多了
You may presume too much.
国王看的不光是战争的结果…
His Majesty, like history, judges us by the outcome of the war...
也很注重作战的过程
...and the manner in which it was fought.
我们为英国皇室打仗，就要有个作战的样子
We serve the Crown, and we must conduct ourselves accordingly.
我们要善待投降的士兵
Surrendering troops will be given quarter.
这种惨无人道的事必须停止！
These brutal tactics must stop!
我百战百胜还不够吗？
Is it not enough that I have never lost a battle?
你为我作战…
You serve me...
你作战的方式会影响别人对我的看法！
...and the manner in which you serve me reflects upon me!
我以为像你这样的名门子弟…
I would've thought that a gentleman from a family as esteemed as yours...
应该了解这点才是
...would understand that.
我父亲把我的遗产
My late father squandered any esteem in which we were held...
和自尊挥霍一空
...along with my inheritance.
打胜仗是我力争上游的方式
I advance myself only through victory.
你要靠我的战功才能得利
You advance yourself only through my good graces.
殖民地的人民是我们的弟兄
These Colonials are our brethren.
战争结束之后我们会重修旧好
And when this conflict is over, we will re-establish commerce with them.
懂吗，上校？
Do you understand, colonel?
懂，大人
Perfectly, my lord.
牧师，如你允许，我想宣布一件事
Reverend, with your permission, I'd like to make an announcement.
年轻人，这是上帝的圣地
Young man, this is a house of God.
我了解，牧师，请容我道歉
I understand that, reverend. I apologize.
我们来召集南卡民兵
The South Carolina Militia is being called up.
有志加入的人请来我这儿登记
I'm here to enlist every man willing.
年轻人…
Son...
我们在这里
...we are here to pray...
为在外面被吊死的人祷告
...for the souls of those men hanging outside.
为他们祷告吧
Yes, pray for them.
但加入我们不要让他们白死
But honour them by taking up arms with us.
让人民吃更多苦？
And bring more suffering to this town?
如果英王乔治能吊死那些人 他就能吊死我们
If King George can hang those men, he can hang any one of us.
丹史考特…
Dan Scott...
一周前，你大赞独立自主两小时
...barely a week ago you railed for two hours about independence.
哈伟先生，你在我家提及过
Mr. Hardwick, how many times have I heard you...
多少次自由？
...speak of freedom at my father's table?
这里半数的人包括你父亲…
Half the men in this church, including you, Father...
和你，牧师…
...and you, reverend...
都和我一样爱国
...are as ardent patriots as I.
你们现在却只敢空谈吗？
Will you now, when you are needed most, stop at only words?
你们是这种人吗？
Is that the sort of men you are?
我要求你们起而行…
I ask only that you act upon the beliefs...
贯彻你们的理念…
...of which you have so strongly spoken...
为你们的信仰奋斗
...and in which you so strongly believe.
谁要加入我们？
Who's with us?
霍华先生
Mr. Howard.
先生…
Sir...
我可以写信给安吗？
...may I have permission to write to Anne?
我可以写信给安吗？　可以
- May I have permission to write Anne? - Yes.
你可以…
You have permission...
写信给我
...to write me.
写给她
Oh, write her.
很好
Very well.
谢谢你，先生
Thank you, sir.
牧师？
Reverend?
牧羊人要保护他的羊群
A shepherd must tend his flock.
有时要赶走野狼
And, at times, fight off the wolves.
你确定这是合适的地方去找民兵吗？
Are you sure this is the right place to recruit for a militia?
天佑吾王！
God save King George!
我想是来对地方了
I think we came to the right place.
有没有赏金？　这次恐怕没有赏金
- Any bounty? - No scalp money this time, Rollins.
但你杀了红衫军
But you can keep
就可以卖给我他们的枪和装备
or sell me the muskets and gear of any Redcoat you kill.
他们在艾克华斯吊死我弟
They hanged my brother down in Acworth.
那些红衫军都该死
Every damned one of them Redcoats deserves to die.
那就加入我们　　我浑身残疾…
- Sign up. - With all my ailments...
我撑不到前哨战，我看还是算了
...I wouldn't make it through the first skirmish. No, sir.
但是我的黑奴可以代我上阵
But you can have my Negro. He'll fight in my stead.
欧坎！过来
Occam! Get over here.
他不聪明，但很强壮
Ain't overly smart. He's strong as a bull.
你会写字吗？
Can you write?
不会
No, no, sir.
那就画押吧　　为什么？
- Well, then, make your mark. - Why?
我把他让给你了
I just signed him over to you.
你愿意的话，我想要你画押
If you're willing, make your mark.
这样就行了
That'll do.
我要去杀红衫军
I'll kill me some Redcoats.
我相信你会
I believe you would.
你几岁？
How old are you?
还不够大，但时候会到的
Not quite old enough. But his time will come.
约翰・比林斯，我希望你会来
John Billings. I was hoping you'd turn up.
传说有20名红衫军…
There's a story going around about 20 Redcoats...
被鬼杀了
...got killed by a ghost or some damn thing.
这鬼带一个印第安斧头
Carried a Cherokee tomahawk.
你相信鬼故事，不嫌老吗？
Aren't you a little old to be believing in ghost stories?
你找到几个？
How many did you get?
12个
Twelve.
很好
Good.
我们要的不是这种人
These men, they're not the sort we need.
我们要的正是这种人
They're exactly the sort we need.
他们以前打过这种仗
They've fought this kind of war before.
那我呢？我也是之一吗？
What about me? Am I one of that sort?
当然不
Hell, no.
你这种人把耻辱带给那种人
Your sort gives that sort a bad name.
我要求快狠准
I want accuracy and precision.
准备！
Make ready!
瞄准！
Take aim!
开火！
Fire!
悬赏：抓鬼
悬赏：抓鬼，亲爱的安：
Dear Anne:
亲爱的安：
我们的军力越来越强
Our force continues to grow.
只要我们奋战不懈，其它人就会起而效尤
As long as we continue to fight, others will come to fight beside us.
我很想见你和跟你说话
I long to see you and speak to you.
也希望我能因职务之便靠近你
I'm hopeful that our duties will bring me near you.
在见面之前，我会时时想着你
Until then, I am and will remain most affectionately yours.
佳百列上
Gabriel.
我们投降！
We surrender!
不！天啊，不要！
No! God, stop!
看在老天的份上…
For the love of God, we...
这些人就要投降了！
These men were about to surrender!
也许吧
Perhaps.
我们永远也无从得知
We will never know.
这是谋杀！
This is murder!
牧师，他们是红衫军，他们罪该万死
Hell, reverend, they're Redcoats. They've earned it.
我们比他们好多了　　你对战争懂什么？
- We're better than that. - What do you know about war?
我知道为崇高目标而战…
I know the difference between fighting...
回你的教堂！
Go back to church!
安静！
Quiet!
他说得对
He's right.
我们要收容那些受伤及投降的英军
Quarter will be given to British wounded and any who surrender.
当他们对我的妻儿坐的船开火时
They gave no quarter when they fired on a ship
也没想到要手下留情
carrying my wife and daughters.
我在200码外眼睁睁看着他们被烧死
I watched from 200 yards off as they were burned alive.
我很同情你，但就这样…　去你的同情
- All my sympathy, but my order stands. - Damn your sympathy.
你凭什么下这种命令？
Who are you to give such an order?
我知道你和你手下在维尔德尼斯堡…
I know what you did to
是怎么对我的同胞
my countrymen at Fort Wilderness.
我们是民兵，不是正规军
We're militia. This is not regular army.
这里的人可以自行决定去留
Every man here is free to come and go as he pleases.
但你们留下来的话…
But while you're here...
就要听我的命令，否则军法处置
...you will obey my command or I will have you shot.
该死的狗辈！　杀了它们！
- Damn dogs! - Shoot the damn things!
别开枪　　它们不让任何人靠近车
- Stay that pistol. - They won't let you near the wagon.
是兰姆酒　　难怪它们看的这么紧
- Rum, Madeira. - No wonder they were guarding it.
军官的制服
Officers' uniforms.
你们猜这值多少钱？
What you think all this is worth?
这是康瓦理斯将军的私人物品
It's the personal correspondence of Lord Cornwallis.
这是他的日记
This is his journal.
我们喝了他的酒，吃了他的狗
I say we drink the wine, eat the dogs
用这些纸来塞毛瑟枪
and use the papers for musket wadding.
吃他的狗？
Eat the dogs?
狗肉很好吃
Dog is a fine meal.
我的天啊
Good heavens.
我这里有地图
I have some maps here for you.
放在那里，谢谢
Put them down over there. Thank you.
给你一把毛瑟枪
Here. A proper musket for you.
我不知道你们怎么样
I don't know about you,
但我觉得不该让黑奴拿枪
but I don't like the idea giving muskets to slaves.
你对自由一点概念都没有
Your sense of freedom is as pale as your skin.
别听他们的
Don't listen to them.
打赢这场仗很多事都会变
If we win this war, a lot of things will change.
什么会变？
What will change?
他们说这里是新大陆，不是
They call this the New World. It's not.
这里和旧大陆一样
It's the same as the old.
但我们有机会建立新世界
But we'll have a chance to build a new world.
新世界中人人平等
A world where all men are created equal under God.
平等
Equal.
听起来很不错
Sounds good.
我刚刚看了天才的杰作
I've just been in the mind of a genius.
康瓦理斯对战争的知识丰富得令人咋舌
Cornwallis knows more about warfare than we could learn in a dozen lifetimes.
那倒是令人振奋的好消息
That's cheerful news.
他在坎登和查理士城的胜利无懈可击
His victories at Camden and Charles Town were perfect. Perfect.
而且他心里明白
And he knows it, what's more.
也许这就是他的弱点
Perhaps that's his weakness.
长官？
Sir?
骄傲
Pride.
骄傲是弱点
Pride's a weakness.
我还是希望他蠢一些
Personally, I would prefer stupidity.
骄傲就行了
Pride will do.
做好了
Finished, my lord.
我把背后改紧…
I've taken it in at the back...
加了肩章和金边
...added wider epaulets and looped gold braiding.
这简直是马用的毛毯　　这我就不知道了
- It's a horse blanket. - I don't know, my lord.
看起来很不错
It's really quite nice.
非常不错　　这是一条很好的马毛毯
- Very nice, my lord. - Very well. It's a nice horse blanket.
塔维顿上校，为什么都等了六个星期…
Colonel Tavington, why, after six weeks...
我还在南卡参加舞会
...am I still attending a ball in South Carolina...
而我现在应该早就在北卡了
...when I should be attending balls in North Carolina?
先是我的行李被偷…
First, the theft of my baggage...
包括我费尽心力写的日志
...including my memoirs, on which I spent countless hours.
接着从这儿到查理士城
Then half the bridges
半数以上的渡口及桥梁都被烧了
and ferries between here and Charles Town burned.
如果你无法对抗民兵，保护补给线…
If you can't protect our supply lines against militia...
你要怎么对抗正规军和法军呢？
...how do you intend doing so against the Regulars or the French?
他们不打正规战，我们找不到他们
They won't fight like Regulars. We can't find them.
他们是民兵
Colonel, they're militia.
他们是拿着耙子的农夫！
They're farmers with pitchforks!
他们不止是农夫
They're rather more than that, I'm afraid.
他们是鬼影指挥官调教的
Made so by their commander, this ghost.
鬼，鬼，鬼
Oh, ghost, ghost, ghost.
那个鬼是你塑造出来的
You created this ghost, colonel.
他的阶级是你帮他挂的
Your brutality swelled his ranks.
要是没有他们就没有这个鬼…
Without them this ghost would've disappeared...
而我现在已到北卡了！
...and I'd be in North Carolina by now!
我要为我辩护…
In my defence, my lord...
够了…！
Oh, enough, enough!
亏你是个好军人居然会怕鬼
A fine soldier you are, bested by a bedtime story.
把那个马毛毯给我
Give me the horse blanket.
奥哈拉，我们的补给船似乎来了
O'Hara, our supply ship appears to have arrived.
是的
Yes, my lord, it has.
那我为什么要穿这个地毯？
Then why am I still wearing this rag?
长官，您的礼服在船上，但是…
Your replacement wardrobe is aboard ship, but...
塔维顿上校认为要先搬军用品
...Colonel Tavington thought it best to secure our arms and munitions first.
弟兄们现在正在搬
They are being unloaded.
你穿这个颜色很好看
You look good in that colour.
臭死了
It stinks.
原来是死人穿的
Well, it's had a dead man in it.
那些野蛮人连你的狗都不放过？
The beasts took your dogs too?
是的
Yes.
那两只好狗是国王送我的
Fine animals. A gift from His Majesty.
据我所知，大概已经死了
Dead now, for all I know.
没有天理了吗？
Is there no decency?
太棒了！是烟火
Oh, fireworks. Lovely!
霍华先生
Mr. Howard.
我是来看安的
I've come to call on Anne.
我是来看安的！
I've come to call on Anne!
你当然是个男人
Well, of course you call yourself a man.
父亲，别逗了，你听到他说的
Father, stop it. You heard him.
这个嘛…
Well...
去看她吧
...call on her.
我快好了
I'm nearly finished.
别担心，父亲
You needn't worry, Father.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
我觉得这布丁袋是很好的传统
Bundling bags are a wonderful tradition.
我一点都不介意
I don't mind in the least.
不要动
Be still.
要茶吗？
Tea?
麻烦你
Please.
好了
There.
来吧，亲爱的
Come, dear.
很好
It's very good.
你喜欢我就放心了
I'm pleased that you like it.
彼德
Peter.
别担心，我的针上工夫比我妈好
Don't worry. I sew better than my mother did.
希望如此
I hope so.
如果你只是站在那里…
If you're just gonna stand there...
为什么不念出来给我们听？
...why don't you read it for us?
我不识字
I can't read.
我会
I can.
请注意
"Take notice.
华盛顿将军及大陆会议下令…
By order of General Washington and the Continental Congress...
在独立军中…
...all bound slaves who give minimum one year service...
服役一年以上的奴隶…
...in the Continental Army...
将可重获自由…
...will be granted freedom...
并可得到每个月五先令的薪水
...and be paid a bounty of five shillings for each month of service."
你听到了吗？
Did you hear that?
先是要放他们自由，接下来又要付他们钱
First they'll free them, then they'll pay them.
只要再六个月
Only another six months.
你自由后要做什么？
What will you do with freedom?
这是我帮你做的
I made this for you.
好好照顾你妈
Look after your mother.
你知道吗，彼德…
You know, Peter...
我没有办法付你钱
...I can't pay you for this.
你方便时再给
Benjamin, you pay me what you can, when you can.
感激不尽
I'm obliged.
佳百列真的很像你
Gabriel sure reminds me a lot of you.
不，他比较像他妈
No, no, he's more like his mother.
下士！
Corporal!
你慢慢来，狗儿们
Take your time. Dogs.
先生
Sir.
道路封闭了
This road is closed.
这些车辆现在正式成为独立军的财产
These wagons now belong to the Continental Army.
准备！
Ready arms!
排成两列
By twos!
你和你的手下不必死，留下车子就走吧
There's no need for your men to die. Leave the wagons and go.
这是国王的公路
This is the king's highway.
我劝你和你的手下让开
And I advise you and your men to make way.
进攻！
Charge!
开火！
Fire!
撤退！
Retreat!
保留实力！
Save yourselves!
撤退！
Retreat!
有埋伏…！
Ambush! Ambush!
我统计了一下
I have the count.
死了二十二个人
22 are dead.
十八个人受伤，二十人失踪
18 wounded and 20 are missing.
我不干了
I'm through.
他不是最后一个要走的人
He won't be the last to leave.
相信我，我的同胞很快就会到
Trust me. Soon my countrymen will arrive.
法国军队…　你下地狱
- The French army is... - To hell with you.
法国军队下地狱
And to hell with the French army.
我们不需要他们
We don't need them.
我们有班杰明・马汀
We got Benjamin Martin.
我们知道他是怎么对付法国人的
We know what he done to the French.
父亲
Father.
你在维尔德尼斯堡的英勇事迹，人人佩服
Men always buy you drinks because of what happened at Fort Wilderness.
陌生人都比我了解你
Strangers know more about you than I do.
告诉我当时的情况
Tell me what happened.
你出生时，你母亲也问过我这个问题
Your mother asked me that question around about the time you were born.
我当时烂醉如泥才会回答
I was drunk and foolish enough to answer it.
法国人和印地安人突击蓝桥
The French and the Cherokee had raided along the Blue Ridge.
英国殖民到查尔斯堡寻求庇护
The English settlers had sought refuge at Fort Charles.
我们抵达时那里已经没人了
By the time we got there, the fort was abandoned.
他们一周前就离开了
They'd left about a week before.
但是我们发现…
But what we found was...
继续说
Go on.
他们杀光所有的男的殖民
They'd killed all the settlers, the men.
女人和…
With the women and...
某些孩童被他们…
...some of the children, they had...
我们把他们的遗骸全埋了
We buried them all, what was left of them.
我们在维尔德尼斯堡追上他们
We caught up with them at Fort Wilderness.
我们好整以暇
We took our time.
把他们五马分尸
We cut them apart slowly.
千刀万剐
Piece by piece.
他们的脸庞历历在目
I can see their faces.
耳边仿佛回荡着他们的尖叫
I can still hear their screams.
我们只留了两个活口
All but two. We let them live.
我们让那两个人
We sent the heads on a pallet...
带着那些人的项上人头回去
...with the two that lived back to Fort Ambercon.
眼睛，舌头，手指…
The eyes, tongues, fingers...
我们则装在篮子里
...we put in baskets.
送到印地安人那儿去
Sent them down the Asheulot to the Cherokee.
不久后，印地安人便不再与法国人合作
Soon after, the Cherokee broke their treaty with the French.
我们就是这样平衡的
That's how we justified it.
我们是…
We were...
英雄
...heroes.
那些人请你喝酒
And men bought you drinks.
我每天都在祈求上帝宽恕我
Not a day goes by where I don't ask God's forgiveness for what I did.
托马斯是我的弟弟，也是你的儿子
Thomas was my brother, as well as your son.
你也许不信，但我和你一样想要报仇
You may not believe this, but I want satisfaction as much as you do.
但在不影响原则下
But not at the expense of our cause.
仇终究是要报的
There will be a time for revenge.
但在那之前我会为自由奋斗
But until then, stay the course.
我喝醉或发脾气时，你妈会说这句话
Your mother said that when I'd get drunk or lose my temper.
我挑托马斯毛病时她会这么说
She'd say it to me when I picked on Thomas.
我好想他
I miss him.
我们有十八名弟兄在卡罗莱纳州堡被俘
The British got 18 of our men at Fort Carolina.
除非他们说出我们下落，否则都会被吊死
They'll be hung one at a time until they give up the rest of us.
牧师…
Reverend...
能帮我写封信吗？
...can you write a letter for me?
写给我太太和儿子　　没问题
- To my wife and boy. - Yes, of course I will.
不过，我们先来祷告
But first let us pray.
大人…
My lord...
大门外有一名骑士
...there is a rider at the gates.
一名举白旗的平民
A civilian carrying a white flag.
我很忙
I am occupied.
他带了两只狗
He has a pair of dogs with him.
是大丹狗
Great Danes.
主啊…
And dear Lord...
请在这个危急的时刻，保佑我们
...protect us in this, our hour of need.
我们以圣父，圣子…
This we ask in the name of the Father, the Son...
和圣灵之名求您
And the Holy Ghost.
在这里等
Wait here.
康瓦理斯将军马上来
General Lord Cornwallis will be with you shortly.
木星，土星，来
Jupiter, Mars. Come, boys.
来
Come.
我的乖狗狗，你们似乎没有吃苦
My good boys. My brave boys. You seem to be well fed.
谢谢你
I thank you for that.
我还不知道你的名字
I'm afraid I don't know your name.
我是独立军上校，你只要知道这个就够了
I'm a colonel in the Continental Army. My rank should be sufficient for now.
随你便
As you wish.
请坐
Please be seated.
谢谢
Thank you.
请你开始说明来意吧？
Would you, as the initiating officer, care to begin?
我会的，除非你要先申报你的损失
I will, unless you'd like to claim aggrieved status.
是的，我要先这么做
Yes, I would like to claim aggrieved status.
那么，请继续吧
Very well, sir. Proceed.
你手上有我的私人物品，包括衣服…
You have in your possession belongings of mine including clothing...
家具及私人日志…
...furniture, personal effects of a non-military nature...
我希望你能还我
...which I'd like returned to me.
我会尽快办到的
Indeed. I will do so as soon as possible.
谢谢
Thank you.
现在我们来谈谈，你们在战场上…
Now we come to the matter of the specific targeting...
针对我们军官开枪的事
...of officers during engagements.
你应该知道在文明战争中，战场上军官…
You must know that in civilized warfare, officers in the field...
不该表现出不合时宜的敌意
...must not be accorded inappropriate levels of hostile attention.
你认为怎样才叫做不合时宜的敌意？
To your mind, what are appropriate levels of hostile attention?
想想看，要是群龙无首…
Imagine the chaos that would follow...
两军相争时，会如何混乱
...from leaderless armies having at each other.
一定要有指挥官…
There must be gentlemen in command to lead...
才能够在必要时控制军队
...and, where necessary, restrain their men.
例如，不让他们欺凌老弱妇孺
Restrain them from, say, targeting civilians. Women, children and such.
那又是另一回事了
That's a separate issue.
不，我认为是同一件事
No. I consider them linked.
只要你的手下攻击平民百姓…
And as long as your soldiers attack civilians...
我就会命令我手下，开战时屠杀你的军官
...I will order the shooting of officers at every engagement.
我的手下都是神枪手
And my men are excellent marksmen.
那好
Very well.
让我们继续讨论…　战俘交换事宜
- Now, let us move on to... - Prisoner exchange.
先生？
Sir?
我这边确有18名犯人，我要你放了他们
You have 18 of my men. I want them back.
我这边的确有18名死囚
I do have 18 criminals under sentence of death...
但我绝对不会扣留战犯
...but I hold no prisoners of war.
如果你拒绝，你就要为你18名军官的死负责
If that's your position, 18 of your officers will have to die.
19名，如果你把我一起吊死
Nineteen, if you hang me with my men.
我的军官？
My officers?
先生
Sir.
在你左方的山顶的树下
Top of the ridge, to your left. Below the tree line.
他们的名字和官阶？
Their names and ranks?
他们不透露姓名，有九名少尉
They refused to give names. There are 9 lieutenants,
五名上尉，三名少校…
5 captains, 3 majors...
和一个说我厚颜无耻的…
...and one fat colonel who called me...
肥上尉
...a cheeky fellow.
这不是绅士该有的作为
This is not the conduct of a gentleman.
如果你军官的作为…叫绅士作风
If the conduct of your officers is the measure of a gentleman...
那我觉得，你这是天大的恭维
...I'll take that as a compliment.
去带我的手下来
Get my men.
安排交换事宜　　大人
- Arrange the exchange. - My lord.
谢谢你
Thank you, sir.
释放囚犯！
Release the prisoners!
将军，这是做什么？　交换战俘
- What is this? - Prisoner exchange.
他俘掳了我们十八名军官
He has 18 of our officers.
他是谁？我看过他
Who is he? I recognize him.
他是民兵的指挥官
He's the commander of the militia.
就是你说的鬼　　不要动，上校！
- Your ghost. - Stay that sword, colonel!
他举着白旗前来谈判，没有敌意　是吗？
He rode in under a white flag for formal parley.
这太疯狂了
This is madness.
如果你伤害他，会害死我们的军官
If you harm him, you condemn our officers.
请恕我说一句，他过去杀了不少军官
With respect, sir, he's killed as many officers in the last two months.
他没有敌意，所以我们不能伤害他
He has shown no aggression here. Hence he cannot be touched.
他没有吗？
Has he not?
你！
You!
原来你就是那个鬼，我记得你
So you're the ghost, are you? I remember you!
在农场上！那个笨小孩
On that farm! That stupid little boy!
他死了吗？
Did he die?
你知道吗…
You know...
有时克尽职责实在很不好受
...it's an ugly business, doing one's duty.
但有时候…
But just occasionally...
是赏心乐事
...it's a real pleasure.
在这场战争结束之前，我会杀了你
Before this war is over, I'm going to kill you.
为什么要等？
Why wait?
很快的
Soon.
出发！
Move out!
我还是觉得，北进太鲁莽
But I still think it's imperative to push north.
这是我们被俘的军官之一
One of our captured officers, my lord.
你们的无能，害我脸上无光！
My reputation suffers because of your incompetence!
那家伙羞辱我！
That man insults me!
这乡巴佬还真不简单
Quite impressive for a farmer with a pitchfork, wouldn't you say?
我要你去找他
I want you to find that man.
我要你把他捉来
I want you to capture him.
人民对他很忠心
The man has the loyalty of the people.
他们保护他和他的家人
They protect him. Protect his family.
保护他手下的家人
Protect the families of his men.
我可以帮你捉到他
I can capture him for you.
但这就要用到一些不太光明的手段…
But to do so requires the use of tactics that are somewhat...
大人之前是怎么说的？
What was the word your lordship used?
好像说“残忍”
"Brutal," I think.
继续
Go on.
我准备好去做该做的事
I am prepared to do what is necessary.
我愿意为我的行为负全责…
I alone will assume the full mantle of responsibility for my actions...
我不受上级指挥…
...free of the chain of command...
不管我做什么，你都不能怪我
...rendering you blameless.
如果…
However...
我这么做…
...if I do this...
我们两个都知道，我永远无法载誉归国
...you and I both know that I can never return to England with honour.
我将会有何下场？
What, I wonder, is to become of me?
当这里的战争结束之后…
When this war is over here in the Colonies...
新兴贵族…
...the new aristocracy...
将会是地主
...will be landowners.
告诉我俄亥俄州的事
Tell me about Ohio.
让开
Make way.
稍息
As you were.
威尔金，离维克菲尔七英哩处…
Wilkins. A plantation seven miles from Wakefield, on the Santee...
山提河东岸的黑沼泽，是什么人住的？
...east of Black Swamp. Who lived there?
班杰明・马汀
Benjamin Martin.
他就是我们说的鬼
He's the ghost.
你对他知道多少？
What do you know about him?
无所不知，我连他几号鞋都知道
Hell, everything. I could tell you the size of his boot.
他有家人吗？他把孩子藏在哪里？
Does he have family? Where would he hide his children?
他的小姨子有一个农庄
His wife's sister has a plantation.
不远
It's not far.
夏绿蒂阿姨，醒醒，有人来了！
Aunt Charlotte! Wake up, someone's coming!
去叫孩子们
Get the boys.
玛格莉特，快来
Margaret, come quickly.
我们走　　孩子们，来吧
- Let's go. - Boys, come.
快！
Go.
跟着我
Stay close.
走这边，从窗台下出去
This way.
跟着我
Follow me.
我们下楼到厨房
We'll go downstairs to the kitchen.
玛格莉特，快！从这下面！快！
Margaret, quick! Get down there! Fast!
山缪，快下来！
Samuel, get down there fast!
在下面，那里
Beneath the sill. There.
房子里没有人
There's no one in the house.
他们一定没走远
They can't be far.
去树林里找找
Search the outbuildings and the woods, quickly.
准备放火烧房子
Prepare to fire the house.
快走
Go.
这是他们家里的奴隶
This one's head of the house slaves.
他们躲在哪里？
Where are they hiding?
继续找，他们一定在附近！
Keep looking! They're here somewhere!
佳百列　　父亲呢？
- Gabriel. - Where's Father?
放火烧房子！
Torch the house!
上马！
To horse!
跟我来，不要紧的
Come on! It's all right.
苏珊，过来
Susan, come here.
夏绿蒂！
Charlotte!
他们不会放弃找我们的
They won't stop looking for us.
我们会带你们去安全的地方
You'll be safe where we're taking you.
父亲说在那里藏身最适合了
Father said it was a perfect place to hide.
他还好吗？
How is he?
我不知道，我是他的儿子
I don't know. I'm his son.
父亲呢？
Where is Father?
几个月前开始说话
Speaking for months now.
Speaking for months.
他到哪里去了？
Why did he go?
他不要那些人找到你们
He didn't want those mean men to find you,
所以他引他们离开
so he led them away.
他会尽快回来看你们
He'll come see you as soon as he can.
我不管，我恨他
I don't care. I hate him.
苏珊，你不恨他
Susan, you don't hate him.
我恨他，我希望他永远不回来
I hate him, and I hope he never comes back.
是孩子们
It's the children.
艾比佳！
Abigale!
你还活着！
You're alive!
我知道不多，但你可以跟我一起
I know it's not much, but you can stay here with me.
很美
It's beautiful.
谢谢
Thank you.
她说话了，苏珊跟你说话了？
She spoke. Susan talked to you?
整句
In full sentences.
好像她一直都可以说话
As if she'd been speaking all along.
可恶，我居然不在场
Damn, I wasn't there for it.
她说什么？
What did she say?
她说…
She said...
她很爱你也很想你…
...that she loves you and misses you...
她也了解你为什么不能来陪她
...but understands why you can't be with her.
天啊，真的吗？
My Lord, she said that.
真不可思议
Isn't that something?
塔维顿有我们的名单，在烧我们的房子…
Tavington has a list of our men. He's burning our homes...
若有不从，格杀勿论
...killing whomever resists.
在哪里？　他烧了山提河岸的七栋房子
- Where? - Seven homes along the Santee so far.
约翰
John.
现在不是报仇的时候
John, this is not a time for vengeance.
是哀悼的时候
This is a time for mourning.
约翰
John.
不！
No!
去照顾你们的家人
Attend to your families.
所有的人都放一周假
One week furlough for all men.
如果收假时，不回来的人
Any man who does not return
不会当你是懦夫临阵脱逃
will not be thought a coward or uncommitted.
父亲！
Father!
爸爸！
Papa!
天啊，他们长得好大，你给他们吃什么？
They're huge. What have you been feeding them?
他们有爸爸的优良血统
They're from good stock on their father's side.
苏珊？
Susan?
我看到了，在那里，快看，父亲！
I see it. There it is. Look. Look, Father.
我抓到了…！
I got it! I got it!
你抓到了
You got it.
我抓到了！
I got it!
小心　　我抓到了
- Careful. - I caught it.
鱼都在这里　　我们去抓
- All the fish are over here. - Let's get them.
父亲，什么事情改变了你？
Father, what changed you?
你确定我变了吗？
Are you sure I have?
是的，你变了
Yes. You changed.
很简单
That's simple.
是你妈妈
It was your mother.
女人对男人会有很奇怪的影响力
A woman can have a strange effect on a man.
曾经…
There were times...
在你妈身边，我连呼吸都有困难
...I had trouble breathing around your mother.
我了解你的感受
I know the feeling.
你说过…
You once said...
等我成家之后自然会明白
...when I had a family of my own, I'd understand.
你说得对
You were right.
你想告诉我什么？
You're trying to tell me something.
要吃苹果吗？　谢谢
- Apple? - Thank you.
恭喜
Congratulations.
安・派翠莎・霍华…
Anne Patricia Howard...
你愿意嫁给此人为妻？
...will you have this man to be your husband to live in marriage?
你会爱他，照顾他，荣显他…
Will you love, comfort and honour him...
至死方休？
...for so long as you both shall live?
我愿意
I will.
佳百列・艾德华・马汀，你愿娶此女为妻…
Gabriel Edward Martin, will you have this woman to be your wife...
共同生活吗？
...to live together in the covenant of marriage?
你会爱她，安慰她，荣显她至死方休吗？
Will you love, comfort and honour her as long as you both shall live?
我愿意
I will.
我依上帝…
Then by the power vested in me by our mutual faith...
赋予我的权力…
...in the Lord, our God...
宣布你们二人结为夫妻
...I now pronounce you man and wife.
抱歉没有早点告诉你
I'm sorry we didn't give you more warning.
没关系
It's fine.
我有东西要给你
I have something for you.
这是佳百列他妈妈的
It belonged to Gabriel's mother.
好漂亮
It's beautiful.
让我来
Allow me.
这是北极星
It's the North Star.
是天空中唯一不会动的星星
That's the only star in the sky that never moves.
它永远不会动摇
It's constant, unwavering.
为人指引方向
A guide.
我很荣幸
I'd be honoured.
我可以吗？
May I?
你坚持的话　　我坚持
- If you must. - I must.
我能坐在你身边吗？
May I sit with you?
这是个自由的国家
It's a free country.
至少以后会是
Or at least it will be.
我不是我姐
I'm not my sister.
我知道
I know that.
是吗？
Do you?
是的
Yes, I do.
很好
Very well, then.
怎么样？
Well?
什么怎么样？
Well what?
我们很快就在潘布克见
I'll see you in Pembroke soon.
那不够快
Not soon enough.
我现在要靠你了…
I'm counting on you to make sure...
我知道　　知道什么？
- I know. - What?
帮我祷告，照顾每个人　　一点都没错
- Say my prayers, take care of everyone. - Couldn't have said it better.
再见
Goodbye.
再见，苏珊
Goodbye, Susan.
再见？
Goodbye?
我只要你说一句话就好了
Just one word, that's all I want.
好吧
All right.
爸爸！
Papa!
爸爸，别走！我什么都说
Papa, don't go! I'll say anything.
求求你，爸爸
Please, Papa.
你要我说什么，我就说什么
I'll say anything you want.
告诉我你要我说什么，我什么都说
Tell me what you want me to say. I'll say anything.
我保证，爸爸，不要走
I promise, Papa. Please don't go.
我保证
I promise.
我会回来的
I'll come back.
我会回来的，你相信我吗？
I'll come back. You believe me?
你让我非常快乐
You know, you make me very happy.
只有我们三个？
Just the three of us?
约翰・蓝斯金来过
John Raskin did come by earlier.
他看了看就走了
He looked around, then he left.
那就四个人了
He would've made four.
四个人会比较好
Four would have been better.
我再撑两个月就满一年了
I got another two months to go before I get to twelve months.
上校
Colonel.
牧师
Reverend.
相信法国人
Trust the French.
是，相信法国人
Yes, trust the French.
还有什么其它机会能杀红衫军？
Where else do I get the opportunity to kill a few Redcoats?
也许趁你不注意时，能杀几个受伤的
Perhaps a few wounded ones when you are not looking.
大家都到教堂去集合
Everyone must gather at the church.
威尔金先生？
Mr. Wilkins?
塔维顿上校有话对村民说
Colonel Tavington wishes to address the whole village.
本镇人民帮助班杰明・马汀和他的叛党
This town has given aid to Benjamin Martin and his rebels.
我要知道他的下落
I wish to know his whereabouts.
所以…
So...
只要有人说出他的下落…
...anyone who comes forward...
我就饶了他的叛国罪
...may be forgiven their treason.
好吧
Very well.
别说我没给过你们机会　　等等！
- You had your chance. - Wait!
他给过他们补给品　　安静！
- This man gives them supplies. - Quiet!
他带他们去黑沼泽　　他说谎！
- He brings them to Black Swamp. - Liar!
就在西班牙教会旁的沼泽
In the marsh, by the old Spanish mission.
这个人吗？
This man here?
是的　　你说黑沼泽？
- Yes. - The Black Swamp, you say?
就在西班牙教会旁的沼泽
By the old Spanish mission.
谢谢
Thank you very much.
把门关上
Shut the doors.
你说会原谅我们
But you said we'd be forgiven.
你是会被原谅！
And indeed you may!
那是你和上帝之间的事
That's between you and God.
我们一定要坚强
Be strong. We must.
我们准备放火烧城了
I'll fire the town on your orders.
烧城？
The town?
把教堂放火烧了
Burn the church.
这样做太不磊落
There's no honour in this.
你不是说，任何背叛英国的人…
Didn't you say all those who stand against England...
都罪该万死吗？
...deserve to die a traitor's death?
放火烧教堂
Burn the church, captain.
把火把拿来
Give me the torch.
荣耀是来自结果，而不是手段
The honour is found in the end, not the means.
这一切会被忘记的
This will be forgotten.
波顿
Bordon.
安！
Anne!
霍尔夫人？
Mrs. Howard?
大家都到哪儿去了？
Where is everybody?
他们不在这里
They're not here.
佳百列走了
Gabriel's gone.
快去拿武器…！
To arms! To arms!
父亲
Father.
不要讲话…
Just don't talk. Don't talk.
父亲
Father.
我很抱歉　　安静
- I'm sorry. - Be quiet.
我会照顾你的，你不会有事的
I'll take care of you. You'll be all right.
托马斯的事我很抱歉
I'm sorry about Thomas.
儿子，那不是你的错
Oh, son, that wasn't your fault.
是我的错
That was mine.
忍着点，你不会有事的
Hold on. You're gonna be all right.
不要死，佳百列
Don't go. Gabriel, don't.
上帝，帮帮我…
Oh, God help me. God help me.
他在哪里？
Where is he?
我来帮你埋了他
I'll help you bury him.
我自己来
I'll bury him.
我太太怀孕了
My wife in Alexandria is with child.
是我们的第一胎
My first.
我为那孩子作战
I fight for that child.
班杰明，没有人能取代你儿子
Benjamin, nothing will replace your sons.
但如果你跟我们来，他们就不会白死
But if you come with us, you can justify their sacrifice.
为什么？
Why?
为何你们会觉得他们不会白死
Why do men feel they can justify death?
是傲慢还是…？
Is it arrogance or?
我长久以来的恐惧…
I have long feared...
就是我旧日的罪愆…会回来纠缠我
...that my sins would return to visit me.
代价之高，我无法承受
And the cost is more than I can bear.
班杰明，我们有机会
Benjamin, we have a chance.
葛林和丹摩根从维吉尼亚来了
Greene and Dan Morgan are down from Virginia.
如果我们打赢下一战，就胜利在望了
If we win this next battle, victory in the war is within our grasp.
那么，去吧
Go, then.
去追求你们的胜利
Seek your victory.
我不重要　　你错了，班杰明
- I'm small issue to it. - You're wrong, Benjamin.
你对你的手下…
You matter to your men...
和对其他人都很重要
...and to others as well.
你的胜利…
Your victories...
和失去的…
...and your losses...
大家都感同身受
...are shared by more than you know.
和我们一起吧
Stay with us.
为自由而战
Stay the course.
我已经为我的理由奋斗过了
I have run my course.
你的手下跟我们走
You men will be leaving with us.
准备出发
Prepare the baggage.
尚
Jean.
你明天不能上，上校
You will be missed tomorrow, colonel.
不能上？　你的伤
- Missed, my lord? - Your wound.
没关系的
It's nothing, my lord.
我随时准备效命
I am, as ever, ready to serve.
很好
Very well.
你最好可以
Make sure you do.
马上就能取得最大一场胜利，别让我失望
I stand on the eve of the greatest victory of my career. Don't fail me.
我的努力，不能把你弄来这里
My efforts in no small measure have brought you here.
我赐给你一次机会
I grant you that small measure...
虽然你没能把鬼带给我
...in spite of your failure to deliver the ghost to me.
从现在开始
Thus far.
我不会再容忍你由于…
I will not tolerate a premature charge...
渴求荣耀而产生的擅断
...born of your eagerness for glory.
等候我的命令
Wait for my order.
不然我就得抛弃所有俄亥俄州的希望
Or you may abandon any hope of Ohio.
明天的战役，将会改变整场战事
Tomorrow's battle can alter the course of the war.
葛林将军，我们究竟会遭遇何种情况？
General Greene, what exactly is the task before us?
各位，我们被康瓦理斯包围了
Gentlemen, Cornwallis has us cornered.
他的人数比我们多
Not only does he outnumber us...
我们的手下几乎全是民兵
...but nearly half of our force is militia.
他们靠不住
Unreliable, at best.
对不起，长官
Excuse me, sir.
你低估了我们的民兵
You underestimate our militia.
你们都一样
All of you do.
我们看过民兵防线接二连三地被击溃
We've seen our militia lines break time and again.
克比斯湾，普林斯顿
Kips Bay, Princeton.
但英国人也这么想
But the British have seen that too.
康瓦理斯的信中，完全看不起民兵
Cornwallis' own letters bear out that he has no respect for the militia.
你有何建议？
What are you suggesting, Ben?
我建议我们利用这点
I'm suggesting we use that.
我知道你们已经牺牲了很多
I know you men have sacrificed a lot so far.
但我只要求你们…
But all I'm asking is that you...
让前两排的民兵开两枪
...let the front line of the militia fire two shots tomorrow.
发射两轮子弹期间，可能会发生很多事
A lot can happen in the time it takes to fire two shots.
特别是在对抗英国正规军时
Especially against British Regulars.
没错，所以我才不叫你们开三枪
Indeed. That's why I'm not asking you to fire three.
如果我死的话，至少死得体面
If I die, I will die well dressed.
开火！
Fire!
大队！　停！
- Battalion! - Company, halt!
哈利…
Harry...
麻烦把这给我的孩子们
...will you give this to my children?
谢谢
Thank you.
现在是十月
It's October now.
我知道
I know.
现在已经超过十二个月了
It's more than 12 months.
你自由了
You're a free man.
我自愿留下来
I'm here now on my own accord.
你愿留下来我很荣幸
I'm honoured to have you with us.
真的很荣幸
Honoured.
举枪！
Shoulder arms!
前进…
Forward...
齐步走！
...march!
你女儿几岁了？
How old were your daughters?
维尔莉特十二，宝琳十岁
Violette was 12 and Pauline, 10.
他们的眼睛都是绿的
They had green eyes.
她们一定很可爱
I'm sure they were lovely.
没错
Yes, they were.
大队！　注意！
- Battalion! - Company!
齐步走！
March!
瞄准！
Fire!
除非我在做梦…
Unless I'm dreaming...
我好像看到…他们队伍中央居然是民兵
...I believe I see militia forming at their centre.
大队！停！
Battalion, halt!
第一排向前！
Dress ranks!
准备！
Make ready!
大队！
Battalion!
停！
Halt!
瞄准！
Take aim!
开火！
Fire!
不要走散！
Hold the line!
准备进攻！　我们还没有接到命令！
- Prepare to charge! - We haven't been given that order.
进攻！
Charge!
塔维顿
Tavington.
他真该死！该死！
Damn him! Damn that man!
瞄准！
Make ready.
开火！
Take aim!
Fire!
开火！
Take aim!
开火！ 撤退！
Fire! Retreat!
上刺刀，看看鹿死谁手
Bayonet charge. We'll see who takes the glory from this field.
进攻！
Charge!
恭喜你，大人
Congratulations, my lord.
叫步兵储备军过来
Infantry reserve into the centre.
我们已经占领了此地
But you've taken the field.
现在我们要打垮他们的士气
Now we'll take their spirits.
叫我们的士兵去击溃他们
Send the battalion over that hill and crush them.
战争今天就要结束
It ends today.
暂停进攻！
Hold the charge!
开火！
Fire!
暂停进攻！
Hold the charge!
开火！
Fire!
瞄准！
Take aim!
开火！
Fire!
进攻！
Charge!
上刺刀！
Charge bayonets!
等等！不要走散！
Halt!
Hold! Dress your ranks!
开火！
Fire!
进攻！
Charge!
撤退！
Retreat!
上校！
Colonel!
我们的军队要瓦解了！
The line is faltering!
撤退…
Retreat! Retreat!
等等！
Wait!
不要撤退！
No retreat!
保持队形！
Hold the line!
推进！
Push forward, men!
叫炮兵到中间集合！
Artillery, concentrate on the centre.
如果我们重新整队朝右前进
If we reform and wheel right,
也许能逼他们撤退
we may be able to turn their flank.
你想得美，将军
You dream, general.
拜托你在战争结束之前杀了我
Kill me before the war is over, will you?
看来你…
It appears you are not...
还是不如我
...the better man.
你说得对
You're right.
我的儿子比你好多了
My sons were better men.
叫他们撤退
Sound the retreat.
叫他们…
Sound...
撤退
...retreat.
亲爱的夏绿蒂
Dear Charlotte:
战事已经改观
The war has turned.
康瓦理斯将军带着手下逃向北方
General Cornwallis took flight with his army and moved north.
我们持续与英军交战在未来数月间…
We continued to engage the British, and in the following months...
康瓦理斯会被困在维吉尼亚州约克镇
...Cornwallis entrenched himself at Yorktown, Virginia.
约克镇，1781年
乔治・华盛顿悄悄地突围到北方
Washington escaped from the north...
包围了康瓦理斯，他无法撤退至海上
...and surrounded Cornwallis, who could not retreat to the seas.
因为我们期待已久的朋友终于抵达
It was blocked off by our long-lost friends...
挡住他的去路
...who had finally arrived.
法国万岁
Vive la France.
自由万岁
Vive la liberté.
大人，我求你
My lord, I beseech you.
你一定要下令投降
You must order the surrender.
怎么可能会变成这样？他们只是杂牌军
How could it come to this? An army of rabble.
庄稼汉
Peasants.
一切都会不同
Everything will change.
一切都不同了
Everything has changed.
虽然他终于还是投降了…
Though he eventually surrendered...
但康瓦理斯无脸见人…
...Cornwallis himself hid in shame...
派他的手下前来投降
...appointing his subordinate to relinquish his sword.
战争就要结束，民兵团即将解散…
With the war ending, and our militia disbanding...
我回顾我们所失去的…
...I take measure of what we have lost...
及我们得到的
...and what we have won.
我希望这么多人的牺牲…
My hope and prayer is that the sacrifices borne by so many...
能够让我们的新国家诞生
...will spawn and fulfil the promise of our new nation.
告诉孩子们，尤其要告诉苏珊
Tell the children, and especially Susan,
我会遵守诺言…
that I will keep my promise...
我很快就会回到你们身边
...as I will be returning to you all soon.
你要去哪里？
Where will you go now?
回家，从头开始
Home. Start over.
你太太就快生了，对吧？
Your wife's expecting a child, isn't she?
她三周前生了个儿子
She gave birth to a son three weeks ago.
你帮他取什么名字？
What'd you name him?
我们叫他佳百列
We named him Gabriel.
谢谢，哈利
Thank you, Harry.
佳百列是个适合农夫的名字
Gabriel is a good name for a farmer.
没错
It is. It is.
尚
Jean.
班
Ben.
佳百列说如果我们打赢的话…
Gabriel said if we won the war...
我们会建立一个全新的世界
...we could build a whole new world.
我想我们就从这里开始…
Just figured we'd get started right here...
从你们的家开始
...with your home.
好主意
Sounds good.
谢谢
Thank you.
夫人
Ma'am.
zeroxia@gmail.com 2006.04.27
Subtitles by SDI Media Group